<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Degang Wang</title>
    <link>https://wangdegang.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Degang Wang</description>
    <image>
      <title>Degang Wang</title>
      <url>https://wangdegang.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://wangdegang.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 15:58:37 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wangdegang.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RWD Statistical Methods</title>
      <link>https://wangdegang.github.io/posts/2023-07-14-stat_rwd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 15:58:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangdegang.github.io/posts/2023-07-14-stat_rwd/</guid>
      <description>Common Statistical Methods in RWD Analysis Regression methods may not be possible Lack of Covariate Information: Regression methods rely on the availability of relevant covariate information to adjust for confounding variables. If important covariates are missing or poorly measured in the observational data, regression methods may not be able to adequately control for confounding.
Nonlinearity or Complex Relationships: Regression models assume linear relationships between the independent variables and the outcome. In observational studies, the relationships between variables may be nonlinear or complex, making it difficult to capture these relationships accurately using regression models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of RWD Sources</title>
      <link>https://wangdegang.github.io/posts/2023-07-10-sum_rwd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 15:58:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wangdegang.github.io/posts/2023-07-10-sum_rwd/</guid>
      <description>RWE is assuming a growing significance in regulatory submissions and reimbursement negotiations, making the availability of fit-for-purpose RWD sources crucial for generating robust evidence to support product development, market access, and post-approval surveillance. As data technology continues to advance, the RWD market has witnessed an influx of new entities. I have compiled a summary of RWD providers that have come to my attention.
Company Data Name Data Type Date Source Country Therapeutic Area Race/Ethnicity Death Lab NPI Adelphi RWE Health Survey Physician survey; chart abstraction; patient reported outcomes Multi Disease specific Yes AmerisourceBergen Intrinsiq EMR Pharmaceutical Distribution Structured and unstructured data from oncology and urology offices US AHRQ HCUP Claims The Healthcare Cost and Utilization Project US Yes Yes AHRQ Social Determinants SDoH 40+ data sources US Yes AllStrips EMR Patient medical records for rare conditions US, Canada Rare Yes Yes Amplity Health RealHealth Data Physician Notes over 50 million medical transcription/physician note records US Yes Yes Yes Anlitiks Claims all-payer claims database, Medicaid claims, ~80% of US claims almost real time US Yes Arcadia EMR linked to Claims integrated claims and EMR from various integrated datahealth system US Yes Yes Yes AHRF Area Health Resources File SoDH US Yes Cardinal Health EMR linked to Claims Inovalon claims linked to EMR from clinical preactices US Yes Yes Yes Yes Carelon HealthCore Oncology EMR Prior authorization forms/documents linked to claims.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
